[{
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Organizations are like living organisms that exist within a dynamic, constantly evolving environment. They are ______, meaning they interact with and are influenced by their surroundings.",
    "answer": "open systems"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "To remain competitive, relevant, and sustainable, organizations must adapt to _______, technological advancements, and market demands.",
    "answer": "societal changes"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The constant need for evolution in organizations is where ______ plays a vital role.",
    "answer": "Organizational Development (OD)"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "In today’s fast-paced world, organizations face rapid ______ advancements, which require staying updated to maintain operational efficiency.",
    "answer": "technological"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "To stay competitive, an organization’s culture must be flexible, responsive, and ______ to change.",
    "answer": "open"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "OD focuses on improving organizational performance, culture, and ______.",
    "answer": "adaptability"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "OD integrates principles of behavioral sciences and strategic management to improve _______, culture, and adaptability.",
    "answer": "organizational performance"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "A publishing house may need to transition from print to digital formats to align with ______ preferences.",
    "answer": "readers'"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Reinvention in organizations involves rethinking and reshaping various aspects, such as _______, policies, culture, and strategies.",
    "answer": "processes"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "The primary goal of OD is to enhance organizational _______, productivity, and adaptability.",
    "answer": "performance"
  }
]
